Hello and welcome.
This session is about Shopify connector.
About one specific capabilities and it's
extremely relevant to customers and
partners in the US. Why? Because in US
the tax system is a sales tax. When
every state and the city and uh
moreover have a different tax rates.
And the Shopify calculates
and Business Central calculate taxes.
So, how to make these two systems work
together because architecture is
completely different.
So, we are introducing some AI
capability to help our US customers uh
to deal with this one.
So, this
tax matching capability will analyze
taxes information received with sales or
with order received from Shopify
and try to find and if not possible to
find, we'll create missing information
and settings in Business Central. And
I'm talking about tax jurisdictions, tax
tax areas and in some cases tax details.
But, let's see in the demo.
Before we start, let me remind you how
Shopify connector deals with taxes.
Even Shopify connector imports tax
information from Shopify, Business
Central still recalculates taxes locally
because it needs to use a right details
when posting
tax information on GL accounts.
So, where we start the details coming
from? It depends on the version. In US
where sales tax is used, and let's look
at this order
for details, uh sales tax information is
coming from the place tax area.
Why tax area? Because in each
geographical position
in US
different tax might exist.
Let's look at this tax code and what we
can see
we can see that it consists of a
multiple levels called tax
jurisdictions. Each jurisdiction can
have a different tax and then all
together impact on the amount of taxes
collected uh from this customer.
So, usually it is a state, city, county,
but number of levels might differ.
What about Shopify connector?
Shopify connector tries to find the
proper tax area code either by looking
at the customer or by country and region
mapping page available from the Shopify
shop card.
But if customer has multiple locations,
might multiple shipping locations, that
might be not precise enough.
It might happen that you need to
maintain a big list of tax areas, which
is a big job, but assigning them to each
individual Shopify orders, it's even
more work.
Let's see how modern AI capabilities can
help you in this assignment.
Let's synchronize orders and pick one
specific order I prepared for this
demonstration.
Let's import it.
And once imported, open it.
And you can see something new.
Couple of notifications telling you that
the tax matching
assigned tax area.
Why? Based on tax jurisdictions. Where
tax jurisdictions are coming from?
It's a very good question, but first
let's scroll down and and notice the new
field, tax area code and tax liable.
Both of them are coming from
uh Shopify and initialized based on
Shopify information and will be used
later when we create sales document. And
you can see the icon indicating that AI
was involved into populating of this
field. We know that
can continue
uh
tax area code was not present when we
looked at the list uh
few minutes before. So, it appears right
now and looks like it was created by
Shopify and it includes It includes
number of tax jurisdictions.
1 2 3. I suspect that each of them has a
tax details with a code with a
tax rate associated, but let's not go
there from here and find a different way
to explore.
I will return back to Shopify order and
notice that I invited to review this
document from my perspective.
There is a review and approve tax match
because I also need to approve
the changes done by AI to this document.
In the tax match review window, I can
see not only the tax area code
which was assigned by that on
three tax jurisdictions, but also the
different lines,
shipping lines, and product lines. I
have only one product, but uh
and taxes associated to each of those.
Apparently, the set of taxes is the same
for shipping and for products, which is
normal.
And you can see that the connector found
tax jurisdiction.
Actually, not found.
It did not found, that's why we can see
this red uh
red icon next to the tax jurisdiction
because it indicates low confidence that
uh
it could not find the right tax
jurisdiction, so it had to create a new
one.
So, it created three tax jurisdictions
and then use them again.
But, all of them are new.
What do I do next? I will approve. I
accept that all of these are correct. I
never had this tax area code in my
system, and I'm missing these tax
jurisdictions, obviously. So, it's good
that somebody, in this case, TaxMatch uh
capability created them for me.
Okay, review done. I can also can cancel
this review if necessary, but I will not
be doing it right now.
Right now, I will be asking myself a
question. Do I really want to review
each document received from Shopify,
assuming that it will be a lot?
Probably not.
Let's take a look at the settings.
This capability,
before we look for them, is actually
very country-specific. It's only
available in US, and it's a shipped as
small Shopify extension, which is only
available in the US, and it's not
published on market source. It will
detect automatically
which localization you are using and
prompt to install if necessary.
Necessary means you are upgrading. If
you got a new installation, it will be
installed by default, and you can see it
in the extension overview.
All right.
Once installed, what is the visual
indication of that in the Shopify shop
card? It's a new fact box.
Let's scroll to the very bottom, and we
have a TaxMatch fact box with a number
of settings. First, do I want to
activate TaxMatch agent? Obviously,
that's what I did first. Then, two more
permissions. Do you want Tax uh
Match agent to create tax jurisdictions?
Maybe you don't want it. Maybe you
prefer to import them from another
sources. Same applies to tax areas. Do
you want to create them, and which
prefix do you want to use? It's
optional, but it helpful to to
distinguish
between uh
automatically created tax areas based on
information received with a Shopify
order,
or tax areas created in a different
traditional way.
And one more parameter which I would
like to discuss is actually how you want
to review it. So, right now it says
always, but I can choose different
option, for example, never.
Or maybe pick something in between
and system will only offer me review if
there is a low confidence. I will not be
able to skip review if there is a
significant issues experienced by
connector. What is it? For example, it
cannot find the matching tax
jurisdiction or tax rate associated with
tax jurisdiction is different. In this
case, it will stop. To illustrate it, I
will choose never and go back to the
list of orders. Right now, I want to
import one more order.
This order includes the same customer,
the same item, so the same shipping
address.
So it will be using the same tax
details. And it means
because we already created an approved
tax area and tax jurisdiction in
previous iteration, it should be good.
Let's click on it and what we can see on
the right in the linked documents that
there is a sum sales document created.
Let's jump to it.
So we are in the sales document and we
getting notification that this sales
document is linked to Shopify order
which was modified by AI. And you might
want to review these changes.
Particularly, it says that tax area was
populated with the help of AI.
And you can see how this decision was
made.
It will open tax match review which is
which we already know with the overview
of used and found tax jurisdictions.
And you can see at this time the
confidence is high. Yeah, obviously, the
tax jurisdiction was found with very
high precision because the name and tax
rate and addresses, a lot of things
match.
All right, I reviewed. I close it.
But before I will go any further,
notice something interesting not related
to taxes but to the
document number used for sales order.
It is exactly the same as a Shopify
order number. So we have a new setting
in this release and you can read about
it in the release notes
or watch video. You can find link in the
description.
All right, let's go back to the list of
orders
and check one more thing. What about
refund? To navigate to refund, I will
open Shopify order
and choose order
refund.
You can see that
link document already present because
sales return document was created. Not
because of taxes again but because
we introduced a new setting as well.
Let's open this a refund document.
AI is not so much involved here. It's
using the same parameters as
we defined on the sales order level. For
convenience, you can see them here in
the new fact box.
All right.
So everything was created automatically
without any review because no issues,
confidence is high. But what if there is
some issue?
Let's imitate Let's construct a
situation when there is some issue.
Let's find some jurisdiction.
Some, for example
this one.
Open it.
Navigate to details.
And here we can see
four lines.
The empty one and non-taxable are
inserted automatically by Business
Central as soon as you create tax
jurisdiction code. There is a setting
which instruct Business Central to do
that. Automatically insert details
lines. But furniture and shipping, they
are inserted by connector. And you can
see they use a document date.
Shipping is the one which is uh
associated with a GL account I used for
shipping charges, and furniture is
associated with item.
Okay, and this one we going to modify
from 3.9, we going to change it to five.
rate
So, now in our Business Central in the
system, the tax rate by default is 5%
for furniture.
Let's go to the list of orders
and choose sync order from Shopify and
import one more order.
This time
system could not create order.
You can see that there is a error
message saying something about uh
tax rate difference. Let's open the
document to look at it into more
details.
Once the document to open, you can see
the notification with the same
information about tax
rates which are different in between
between Business Central and what we got
from Shopify.
You can choose review
to explore. Remember that we decided
that we don't want to review, but this
is a important situation, so we have to.
And we got a lot of red here
which shows that it's a serious
situation. Why serious? Because the rate
in Shopify is different at the rate in
Business Central. So, if we create order
and use
configuration which is available right
now in the Business Central, the total
of document will be different.
And probably we need to make a decision
about it. We can choose approve and keep
a rate configured in Business Central as
is, or we can use the same rate as
available in Shopify.
So, for example, I can transfer
rate 3.9
and override the the one we have inside
Business Central. Of course, this is a
common setting and it will impact other
documents as well, which will be created
on the same day to later.
Uh it uses date of the document when
updating the rate.
Okay.
Looks good. Approve.
And create sales document.
New document created, but we probably
more interested in the
uh comparison page and we can see that
total tax in the Shopify document
is exact match to total tax in the
created sales document.
All right. We saw how AI is helping
merchants
to deal with uh
pretty advanced
tax uh tax system in the US and it helps
you to match sales tax information in
the received order with uh information
in Business Central and create missing
information.
I hope the processing of sales tax uh
will be better
and uh
you will give us
AI capability a try.
Thank you.